

## Adrián Hinojosa Calleja

## Data Scientist | Ph.D. Mathematics

Barcelona - 611 03 31 20 - hinojosa.a@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/adhinojosa hinojosaad.github.io

A Data Scientist and Ph.D. Mathematics specializes in Probability. Machine Learning experience with pandas, statsmodel, and sklearn Python's libraries. +10 years teaching mathematics at different educational levels.

## **Educational Background**

#### **PhD Mathematics**

Universitat de Barcelona, 2022 Cum Laude

#### **Master Mathematical Sciences**

TU Berlin, Germany, 2016

#### **Degree Mathematics**

UNAM, Mexico, 2013 Graduated with honors

#### Certificates

#### **Data Science Bootcamp**

It Academy, 2022

# Introduction to Functional Data Analysis with R

UAB, 2018

## **Technical Skills**

- Python
- R
- SQL
- Java
- LaTex

#### **Soft Skills**

- Problem resolution
- Critical thinking
- Teamwork
- Leadership

## **Work Experience**

#### **Predoctoral Researcher**

Universitat de Barcelona April 2017 to January 2022 Researcher in Stochastic Partial Differential Equations.

## **Mathematics Teacher**

Logos Middle School

August 2012 to June 2014

Teacher of Mathematics I and Mathematics III courses.

Teacher's assistant of Probability and Statistics courses.

## **Organization Experience**

#### **Organizer**

Barcelona's Probability Seminar January 2021 to March 2022

#### Member of the Executive Board

Institut de Matematiques de la Universitat de Barcelona November 2017 to January 2022

## **Data Science Projects**

#### Barcelona Air, 2022

Time Series Analysis of N02 and PM10 concentrations between 2019 and 2022 in a neighborhood of Barcelona. An ARIMA forecasting model was fitted with Python and R.

#### **Space X, 2022**

3rd Place in the Talent Squad-Data Science Challenge. Classification model to predict the states of turbulence from a space rocket. Python's sklearn library was used in this project.